<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<p class="Normal1">This graduate group is administered by the College of Engineering, Materials Science and Engineering Department. The program has three major areas of emphasis: applied physics, engineering science, and mathematical sciences. Faculty associated with the program are drawn from several departments within the College of Engineering, as well as from the Departments of Physics, Chemistry, Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, Statistics, and Mathematics. Topics of interest include the novel properties and applications of nanostructures, thin films and interface science, microelectromechanical systems (MEMS), short wavelength coherent radiation, X-ray micro-imaging for the life and physical sciences, plasma physics and plasma-assisted materials processing, laser-induced chemical processes, laser probing of complex reacting systems, ultrafast phenomena, particle accelerators, nonlinear dynamics, chaotic systems, numerical methods, and topics in computational fluid mechanics and reacting flows. </p>
<p>In addition, students who are admitted to the program may also apply for the Designated Emphasis (DE) in Nanoscale Science and Engineering (DE NSE), Energy, Science, and Technology (DE EST), and Computational Science and Engineering (DE CSE). Students usually apply for these DE during their first or second year of study..</p>
<p>Graduate research in the AS&amp;T Program benefits from state-of-the-art experimental facilities at the Berkeley campus and the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. Among these facilities are the National Center for Electron Microscopy, with the world's highest resolution high-voltage microscope; a microfabrication lab for student work involving lithography, MEMS ion-implantation, and thin-film deposition; an integrated sensors laboratory; femtosecond laser laboratories; optical, electrical, and magnetic resonance spectroscopies; short wavelength laser and X-ray research laboratories; an unparalleled variety of material, chemical, and surface science analytic equipment; and a soft X-ray synchrotron dedicated to materials, chemical, and biological research using high-brightness and partially coherent X-rays. The interdisciplinary, collaborative nature of the AS&amp;T Program provides ample opportunity to develop new research directions by making the best use possible of these facilities and of the other research instrumentation available to AS&amp;T faculty.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Uniform minimum requirements for admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A minimum grade-point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant comes from a country or political entity (e.g. Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, 230 on the computer-based test, 90 on the iBT test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Enough undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants who already hold a graduate degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees as evidence of broad research training, not as vocational training certificates; therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to take up new subject matter on a serious level without undertaking a graduate program, unless the fields are completely dissimilar.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may only apply to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <p>Any applicant who was previously registered at Berkeley as a graduate student, no matter how briefly, must apply for readmission, not admission, even if the new application is to a different program.</p> <h4>Required documents for admissions applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts:  </strong><span style="font-size:1em">Upload unofficial transcripts with the application for the departmental initial review. Official transcripts of all college-level work will be required </span><strong style="font-size:1em">if admitted</strong><span style="font-size:1em">. Official transcripts must be in sealed envelopes as issued by the school(s) you have attended. Request a current transcript from every post-secondary school that you have attended, including community colleges, summer sessions, and extension programs.</span> 	<div class="gmail_default">If you have attended Berkeley, upload unofficial transcript with the application for the departmental initial review. Official transcript with evidence of degree conferral <em><strong>will not</strong></em> be required if admitted.</div> 	</li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants can request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, not the Graduate Division.</li> 	<li><strong>Evidence of English language proficiency:</strong> All applicants from countries in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This requirement applies to applicants from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, and most European countries. However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a U.S. university may submit an official transcript from the U.S. university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement: 1) courses in English as a Second Language, 2) courses conducted in a language other than English, 3) courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and 4) courses of a non-academic nature. If applicants have previously been denied admission to Berkeley on the basis of their English language proficiency, they must submit new test scores that meet the current minimum from one of the standardized tests.</li> </ol>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
<h4 class="Normal1">Curriculum</h4>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%"><tbody><tr class="even lastrow firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Electives per approved study list, according to highly individualized study along such major AS &amp; T areas of concentration, such as as applied physics, engineering sciences, and mathematical sciences</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<coursestext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Applied Science and Technology</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=AST C210" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="567">
<span class="code">AST&#160;C210</span> 
<span class="title">Soft X-rays and Extreme Ultraviolet Radiation</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">This course will explore modern developments in the physics and applications of soft x-rays. It begins with a review of electromagnetic radiation at short wavelengths including dipole radiation, scattering and refractive index, using a semi-classical atomic model. Subject matter will include the generation of x-rays with laboratory tubes, synchrotron radiation, laser-plasma sources, x-ray lasers, and black body radiation. Concepts of spatial and temporal coherence will be discussed.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="567" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Physics 110, 137, and Mathematics 53, 54 or equivalent</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Applied Science and Technology/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> El Engineering 290G</p><p class=""><strong>Also listed as:</strong> EL&#160;ENG&#160;C213</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=AST C225" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="257">
<span class="code">AST&#160;C225</span> 
<span class="title">Thin-Film Science and Technology</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Thin-film nucleation and growth, microstructural evolution and reactions. Comparison of thin-film deposition techniques. Characterization techniques. Processing of thin films by ion implantation and rapid annealing. Processing-microstructure-property-performance relationships in the context of applications in information storage, ICs, micro-electromechanical systems and optoelectronics.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="257" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing in engineering, physics, chemistry, or chemical engineering</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Applied Science and Technology/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Instructors:</strong> Wu, Dubon</p><p class=""><strong>Also listed as:</strong> MAT&#160;SCI&#160;C225</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=AST C239" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="114">
<span class="code">AST&#160;C239</span> 
<span class="title">Partially Ionized Plasmas</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Introduction to partially ionized, chemically reactive plasmas, including collisional processes, diffusion, sources, sheaths, boundaries, and diagnostics. DC, RF, and microwave discharges. Applications to plasma-assisted materials processing and to plasma wall interactions.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="114" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> An upper division course in electromagnetics or fluid dynamics</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Applied Science and Technology/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> 239</p><p class=""><strong>Also listed as:</strong> EL&#160;ENG&#160;C239</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=AST C295R" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="304">
<span class="code">AST&#160;C295R</span> 
<span class="title">Applied Spectroscopy</span> 
<span class="hours">3 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">After a brief review of quantum mechanics and semi-classical theories for the interaction of radiation with matter, this course will survey the various spectroscopies associated with the electromagnetic spectrum, from gamma rays to radio waves. Special emphasis is placed on application to research problems in applied and engineering sciences. Graduate researchers interested in systematic in situ process characterization, analysis, or discovery are best served by this course.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="304" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing in engineering, physics, chemistry, or chemical engineering; courses: quantum mechanics, linear vector space theory</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Applied Science and Technology/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Instructor:</strong> Reimer</p><p class=""><strong>Also listed as:</strong> CHM&#160;ENG&#160;C295R</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=AST 299" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="357">
<span class="code">AST&#160;299</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study or Research</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Investigations of advanced problems in applied science and technology. Sponsored by Engineering Interdisciplinary Studies Center.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="357" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor; graduate standing</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p><p class=""><strong>Summer:</strong> <br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>3 weeks - 5-60 hours of independent study per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>8 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Applied Science and Technology/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

