<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<p>The Graduate Group in Sociology and Demography (GGSD) is an interdisciplinary training program in the social sciences designed for students with broad intellectual interests. Drawing on Berkeley's Department of Sociology and Department of Demography, the Group offers students a rigorous and rewarding intellectual experience.</p>
<p>The Group, founded in 2001, sponsors a single degree program leading to a PhD in sociology and demography. The GGSD helps foster an active intellectual exchange between graduate students and faculty in the two disciplines. In addition, faculty and students associated with the Group often maintain close ties with other disciplines both inside and outside the social sciences (for example, economics, anthropology, statistics, public health, biology, and medicine).</p>
<p>The specific emphasis of this academic program is the intersection of the fields of sociology and demography. Potential areas of study include, but are not limited to, population history, social stratification, inequality, race, ethnicity, causes and consequences of population growth, the demographic transition, population–environment interactions, economic development, immigration, globalization, gender, family, kinship, child welfare, sexuality, intergenerational relations, aging, mortality, health care, disability, fertility, family planning, and birth control.</p>
<p>Students in the GGSD typically earn both an MA in sociology and an MA in demography en route to the PhD in sociology and demography. Students already enrolled in another graduate program at Berkeley who wish to earn a PhD in sociology and demography may apply by requesting a change of major. Students not already enrolled at Berkeley who wish to enter the PhD program should complete the required online application. The general deadlines for application specified by the Graduate Division apply, as do the general requirements of the Academic Senate and the Graduate Division for PhD degree programs.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Uniform minimum requirements for admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A minimum grade-point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant comes from a country or political entity (e.g. Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, 230 on the computer-based test, 90 on the iBT test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Enough undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants who already hold a graduate degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees as evidence of broad research training, not as vocational training certificates; therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to take up new subject matter on a serious level without undertaking a graduate program, unless the fields are completely dissimilar.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may only apply to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <p>Any applicant who was previously registered at Berkeley as a graduate student, no matter how briefly, must apply for readmission, not admission, even if the new application is to a different program.</p> <h4>Required documents for admissions applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts:  </strong><span style="font-size:1em">Upload unofficial transcripts with the application for the departmental initial review. Official transcripts of all college-level work will be required </span><strong style="font-size:1em">if admitted</strong><span style="font-size:1em">. Official transcripts must be in sealed envelopes as issued by the school(s) you have attended. Request a current transcript from every post-secondary school that you have attended, including community colleges, summer sessions, and extension programs.</span> 	<div class="gmail_default">If you have attended Berkeley, upload unofficial transcript with the application for the departmental initial review. Official transcript with evidence of degree conferral <em><strong>will not</strong></em> be required if admitted.</div> 	</li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants can request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, not the Graduate Division.</li> 	<li><strong>Evidence of English language proficiency:</strong> All applicants from countries in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This requirement applies to applicants from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, and most European countries. However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a U.S. university may submit an official transcript from the U.S. university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement: 1) courses in English as a Second Language, 2) courses conducted in a language other than English, 3) courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and 4) courses of a non-academic nature. If applicants have previously been denied admission to Berkeley on the basis of their English language proficiency, they must submit new test scores that meet the current minimum from one of the standardized tests.</li> </ol>
<h3>Admission to the Program</h3>
<p>The Department of Demography requires all applicants to take the general portion of the Graduate Record Examination. Applicants may apply for the Masters in Demography, PhD in Demography or the PhD in Sociology and Demography. </p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3><span>Normative Time Requirements</span></h3>
<h4>Normative Time to Advancement</h4>
<p>Normative time to advancement to doctoral candidacy for the Demography PhD is six semesters from the time the student entered the program.</p>
<h4>Normative Time in Candidacy</h4>
<p>Normative time in doctoral candidacy for the Sociology and Demography PhD degree is four semesters.</p>
<h4>Total Normative Time</h4>
<p>The total normative time of the program is 12 semesters.</p>
<h3>Time to Advancement</h3>
<h4>Curriculum</h4>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%"><colgroup><col class="codecol" /><col class="titlecol" /><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol" /></colgroup><tbody><tr class="even areaheader firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader">Courses Required</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">DEMOG&#160;110</td><td>Introduction to Population Analysis</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">DEMOG&#160;C126</td><td>Social Consequences of Population Dynamics</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">DEMOG&#160;C175</td><td>Economic Demography</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">DEMOG&#160;210</td><td>Demographic Methods: Rates and Structures</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">DEMOG&#160;211</td><td>Advanced Demographic Analysis</td><td class="hourscol">3-4</td></tr>
<tr class="orclass odd"><td class="codecol orclass">or&#160;SOCIOL&#160;271C</td><td colspan="2"> Methods of Sociological Research</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">DEMOG&#160;213</td><td>Practical Computer Applications for Demographic Analysis</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">DEMOG Graduate Elective (from 220 to 289)</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">SOCIOL&#160;200</td><td>Proseminar</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">SOCIOL 201A/201B</td><td>Classical Social Theory</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Select one of the following:</span></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">SOCIOL&#160;202A</div></td><td>Advanced Study in Sociology Theory: Classical Sociological Theory</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">SOCIOL&#160;202B</div></td><td>Advanced Study in Sociology Theory: Contemporary Sociological Theory</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">SOCIOL&#160;202C</div></td><td>Advanced Study in Sociology Theory: Systematic Sociological Theory</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">SOCIOL&#160;271A</td><td>Methods of Sociological Research</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">SOCIOL Graduate Electives (2; from 280 series)</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Electives per approved study list</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h4>Coursework and Preliminary Examination</h4>
<p>During the first year of study students in all Demography and Sociology and Demography degree programs complete the required coursework (24 units) and then take the Preliminary Examination at the end of the spring semester.</p>
<h4>Language Examination</h4>
<p>Each student is expected to demonstrate reasonable reading competence in at least one other than English language that is relevant to demographic studies. Students must pass a language exam before advancing to doctoral candidacy.</p>
<h4>Dissertation Prospectus</h4>
<p>The dissertation prospectus is developed in the context of a research seminar, Demography 295. Doctoral students are expected to enroll in 295 every semester until the prospectus is complete, which should occur within three years after matriculation.</p>
<h4>Oral Qualifying Examination</h4>
<p>The oral qualifying examination for admission to doctoral candidacy should be taken during the second or third year (depending on the time needed for the completion of the student's ancillary Master's program).</p>
<h4>CITI Human Subjects Training</h4>
<p>Students are required to take CITI Human Subjects training as specified by the Office for the Protection of Human Subjects before advancing to doctoral candidacy. For more information please see the OPHS website: http://cphs.berkeley.edu/training.html</p>
<h3>Time in Candidacy</h3>
<h4>Dissertation</h4>
<p>Upon successful completion of the foreign language requirement, the oral qualifying exam, and the prospectus, students enter into the final phase of the program, doctoral candidacy. During this period, students are expected to take another research seminar, <span class="sc_courseinline">DEMOG&#160;296</span>, every semester until the completion of the dissertation. The department does not require a formal defense of the completed dissertation. </p>

<h3>Required Professional Development</h3>
<p class="Normal1">The department does not formally require professional development but all students are encouraged to attend the weekly Demography Brown Bag Presentation Series as well as the monthly Bay Area Colloquium on Population. Students are also encouraged to attend and present papers at the annual Population Association of America Meeting or other demographic conferences.</p>
]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Faculty</h3><h4>Professors</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Joshua Robert Goldstein, <i>Professor</i>.</strong> <p class="facitem"><strong>Ronald D. Lee, <i>Professor</i>.</strong> Economics, evolutionary theory, mathematical demography, population aging, intergenerational transfers, economic demography, life history theory, population forecasting, national transfer accounts.<br /><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14239" target="_blank">Research Profile</a><p class="facitem"><strong>Kenneth Wachter, <i>Professor</i>.</strong> Mathematical demography stochastic models, simulation, biodemography, federal statistical system.<br /><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14563" target="_blank">Research Profile</a><p class="facitem"><strong>John R. Wilmoth, <i>Professor</i>.</strong> Demography, sociology, methodological research, longevity, life expectancy, mortality differentials, familial resemblance, mortality and life expectancy forcasting, historical population trends, world population growth, international migration forecasting.<br /><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15625" target="_blank">Research Profile</a><h4>Associate Professors</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Jennifer Johnson-Hanks, PhD, <i>Associate Professor</i>.</strong> West Africa, marriage, childbearing, demography and culture.<br /><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14898" target="_blank">Research Profile</a>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

