<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<p>In 2013-14 UC Berkeley inaugurated the Designated Emphasis (DE) in Jewish Studies. The DE provides curricular and research resources for students who want to concentrate on Jewish Studies within their respective disciplines and have their work formally recognized in their degree designation. Designed to bring together faculty and students from different departments, the DE is administered by the Graduate Group in Jewish Studies and provides a unique context for rigorous cross-disciplinary research. Students applying to the DE must be prepared to integrate high-level research in Jewish Studies into their coursework, qualifying exam, and dissertation.</p>
<div>
<p>In keeping with UC Berkeley requirements for a Designated Emphasis, students must be admitted to the DE prior to taking their Qualifying Exams. However, because this DE is replacing the Joint Degree Program in Jewish Studies, exceptions will be made for exceptionally qualified and motivated students who have already taken qualifying exams, who are working within established departments, and whose work has an emphasis in an area of Jewish Studies. These “grandfathered” exceptions will be made on a case-by-case basis, on the recommendation of the faculty graduate group. In every case, admission to the DE will be determined on the basis of how coherently and logically the student can articulate the value of the DE for her/his larger course of study and career goals, as well as on the quality of the written work.</p>
</div>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext>
<![CDATA[
<p>To be admitted to the Designated Emphasis in Jewish Studies, an applicant must already be accepted into a PhD program at the University of California, Berkeley. For further information regarding admission to graduate programs at UC Berkeley, please see the <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/" target="_blank">Graduate Division's Admissions website</a>
.</p>

<p>Students will be required to fill out a form requesting admission to the DE, listing their prior preparation in the field, and their projected pathway through the program. In addition, they should submit a brief essay stating interests and reasons for applying, a CV, a writing sample, and a letter of recommendation from a faculty member in the student’s home department indicating why and how the student would benefit from the DE in Jewish Studies.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<designatedemphasisrequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
<p class="Normal1">Students admitted to the Designated Emphasis in Jewish Studies must complete the following requirements before applying for their Qualifying Examination:</p>
<ol>
	<li class="Normal1">Students will be required to complete the course <span class="sc_courseinline">JEWISH&#160;290</span> in the field of Jewish Studies for Graduate Students, which will serve as the integrative course for the program regarding methodology and research skills. This course can be offered by any faculty member of the Graduate Group in the DE in Jewish Studies, and will likely rotate among core faculty. The course topics will thus vary in accordance with the specific expertise of individual faculty member(s). The number of units for this course ranges from 3-8 and is decided on the basis of a mutual agreement between the student and faculty instructor(s) in accordance with the amount of working hours the student intends to dedicate to this course. The course will be a combination of standard seminar format with shared readings and discussion, and individualized research and writing. The goal of this course is thus two-fold:  to provide cohort cohesion and intellectual exchange across disciplines, and to provide the necessary intellectual background for top quality scholarship in the field of Jewish Studies. The course will have a strong practical component, including engagement with bibliographical resources and scholarly practices essential to doing work in the field of Jewish Studies. The student will need to write a 5000-word article to complete the course, using a bibliography that includes Jewish Studies materials. The content of the article will be determined on an individual basis with attention to the students’ research interests. This course will be offered once each year. The faculty members offering <span class="sc_courseinline">JEWISH&#160;290</span> are core members of the Graduate Group for the Designated Emphasis in Jewish Studies.</li>

	<li class="Normal1">Students in the DE will also complete three additional course electives related to Jewish Studies and approved by the Graduate Group’s Curriculum Committee. These courses will support the interdisciplinary nature of the program with attention to the individual students’ research interests. At least one of these courses has to be a graduate seminar. One of the three course electives can be fulfilled by repeating <span class="sc_courseinline">JEWISH&#160;290</span> under the condition that the topic of this course changes. Students will be provided a list of potential electives offered by the different departments sponsoring the DE. A student may petition to the Advising Committee to approve a course not on the established list.</li>

</ol>

<h3 class="Normal1">Examination</h3>
<p class="Normal1">A member of the Graduate Group in Jewish Studies must be a formal member of the PhD Qualifying Examination committee. Under most circumstances, the Graduate Group member in the student’s home department will serve in this function. A member of the Graduate Group may also serve as the outside member of the Qualifying Exam committee if not a faculty member of the student’s major. A Jewish Studies topic must be included as a subject on the Qualifying Examination. Satisfactory performance on the Qualifying Examination for the PhD will be judged according to the established rules in the student’s major program.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Dissertation</h3>
<p class="Normal1">A member of the Graduate Group in Jewish Studies must be a formal member of the dissertation committee. The dissertation must relate to Jewish Studies (History, Literature, Culture, Arts).</p>
]]>
</designatedemphasisrequirementstext>
<coursestext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Jewish Studies</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JEWISH 200" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="16">
<span class="code">JEWISH&#160;200</span> 
<span class="title">Advanced Topics in Jewish Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Graduate seminar will focus on specific areas or topics in Jewish studies through a combination of close reading of texts, student presentation, and informal lectures. Instructors and topics to vary semester to semester. Consult department website for updated course descriptions.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="16" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Jewish Studies/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JEWISH 290" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="587">
<span class="code">JEWISH&#160;290</span> 
<span class="title">Modern Jewish Scholarship: History and Practice</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">This seminar, specifically designed as the ‘integrative course’ for students pursuing the Designated Emphasis in Jewish Studies, will offer an in-depth introduction to some of the central trends and personalities in modern Jewish historiography. We will read (and read about) the founders of modern Jewish historiography, and then explore some contemporary trends in Jewish scholarship, according to the disciplinary affiliations of the students in the class.<br/>
<br/>
In addition to weekly assignments</span><span class="deschide">, students will write a 7000-word paper suitable for publication in a scholarly journal.<br/>
<br/>
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="587" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> This is the required integrative course for doctoral students pursuing the Designated Emphasis in Jewish Studies. It is open to other doctoral students by permission of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2-3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Jewish Studies/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Instructor:</strong> Efron</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JEWISH 296" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="456">
<span class="code">JEWISH&#160;296</span> 
<span class="title">Joint Doctoral Program Dissertation Research and Writing Credit</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">The course is offered to graduate students in the Joint Doctoral Program in Jewish studies to provide course credit for conducting dissertation research and dissertation writing, only after the student has successfully advanced to candidacy.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="456" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Advancement to doctoral candidacy</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Jewish Studies/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p><p class=""><strong>Instructor:</strong> Alter</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JEWISH 299" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="325">
<span class="code">JEWISH&#160;299</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study and Research - Jewish Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 5 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Topics and instructors will vary depending upon area of study. Special individual study for qualified graduate students only. Individual study and research, including fieldwork, in consultation with instructor on subject matter not covered in scheduled course offerings.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="325" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing and consent of instructor</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-5 hours of independent study per week</p><p class=""><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 1.5-9 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Jewish Studies/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JEWISH 602" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="191">
<span class="code">JEWISH&#160;602</span> 
<span class="title">Joint Doctoral Program Independent Study</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">The course is offered to graduate students in the Joint Doctoral Program in Jewish studies to provide opportunities for undertaking independent studies prior to advancement to candidacy.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="191" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Advancement to doctoral candidacy</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-12 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Jewish Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p><p class=""><strong>Instructor:</strong> Alter</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

