<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Minor</h3>
<p>The Program in Medieval Studies offers an undergraduate interdisciplinary Minor in Medieval Studies. The Minor has three principal purposes:</p>
<ol>
	<li>
	<p>To give undergraduate students who have an interest in Medieval Studies the benefit of advising about what courses are available in the various departments and how certain courses might fit together into a meaningful sequence or cluster.</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p>To enable students to be informed about lectures, colloquia, social events, and conferences of interest to them.</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p>To allow those undergraduates who complete substantial work in Medieval Studies to have that fact acknowledged. Should those students wish to pursue further academic work after graduation, their chances of success in the competition for admission to graduate school will be enhanced not just because of the official notice on their transcript but because they will have gained greater professional competence through informed participation in the Medieval Studies program at Berkeley.</p>
	</li>
</ol>
<h3>Declaring the Minor</h3>
<p>Undergraduates who contemplate applying for the Minor should contact the Graduate/Undergraduate Adviser to discuss their interests and needs.</p>
<p>Students may declare the Minor only in their final semester. <span>To declare, download a &quot;Completion of an L&amp;S Minor&quot; form from the <a href="http://ls-advise.berkeley.edu/fp/fp.html" target="_blank">College of Letters and Sciences website</a>
. Students should f</span>
<span>ill out the form and take it to the adviser in their major first. This adviser must certify that the requirements for the Major are fulfilled and sign at the bottom of the form. </span>Then take the form to the Medieval Studies adviser.</p>

]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<minorrequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
<p>​</p>
<p>Students who have a strong interest in an area of study outside their major often decide to complete a minor program. These programs have set requirements and are noted officially on the transcript in the memoranda section, but they are not noted on diplomas.</p>
<h3>General Guidelines</h3>
<ol>
	<li>All courses taken to fulfill the minor requirements below must be taken for graded credit.</li>
	<li>A minimum of three of the upper-division courses taken to fulfill the minor requirements must be completed at UC Berkeley.</li>
	<li>A minimum grade point average (GPA) of 2.0 is required for courses used to fulfill the minor requirements.</li>
	<li>Courses used to fulfill the minor requirements may be applied toward the Seven-Course Breadth Requirement, for Letters and Science students.</li>
	<li>No more than one upper-division course may be used to simultaneously fulfill requirements for a student's major and minor programs.</li>
	<li>All minor requirements must be completed prior to the last day of finals during the semester in which the student plans to graduate. If students cannot finish all courses required for the minor by that time, they should see a College of Letters and Science adviser.</li>
	<li>All minor requirements must be completed within the unit ceiling. (For further information regarding the unit ceiling, please see the College Requirements tab.)</li>
</ol>
<h3>Requirements</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%"><tbody><tr class="even lastrow firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Select five upper-division or graduate courses courses in Medieval Studies</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h3>Recommended Courses</h3>
<p>Students who are contemplating advanced work in Medieval Studies should, if possible, take <span class="sc_courseinline">HISTORY&#160;4B Origins of Western Civilization: Medieval Europe</span>  early in their undergraduate career. Other lower division courses are also recommended (e.g., <span class="sc_courseinline">ITALIAN&#160;30 Dante (in English)</span> and <span class="sc_courseinline">MUSIC&#160;75 History of Western Music: Music to 1700</span>), but only upper-division courses can be counted toward the minor.</p>

]]>
</minorrequirementstext>
<coursestext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Medieval Studies</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=MED ST 150" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="334">
<span class="code">MED&#160;ST&#160;150</span> 
<span class="title">Studies in Medieval Culture</span> 
<span class="hours">2 - 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow ">Normally three hours of lecture per week for fifteen weeks. In the event that the instructor is in residence for fewer than fifteen weeks, the course may be offered for either 2 or 3 units of credit, in proportion to the number of actual contact hours. Course may be repeated for credit. Normally taught by the Visiting Distinguished Professor of Medieval Studies. An interdisciplinary exploration of Medieval culture, focusing on an area of the instructor's expertise. Specific topic varies with instructor.</span><span class="deschide">
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="334" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> <br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>6 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 7.5-10 hours of lecture per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>7.5 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>8 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 4-8 hours of lecture per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>15 weeks - 2-4 hours of lecture per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> One hour of lecture per week per unit. One hour of lecture per week per unit. Two hours of lecture per week per unit for eight weeks. Two and one-half hours of lecture per week per unit for six weeks. Two hours of lecture per week per unit for eight weeks. Two and one-half hours of lecture per week per unit for six weeks.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Medieval Studies/Undergraduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

