<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<p>The Department of East Asian Languages and Cultures offers a PhD program in Japanese Language. The department only admits students into the PhD program.</p>
<div class="content">
<div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
<div class="field-items">
<div class="field-item even">
<p>As a rule, students wishing to enter the graduate program should have completed an undergraduate program comparable to the undergraduate major in this department. Students who do not have B.A. or M.A. degrees in East Asian Languages and Cultures (Japanese or Chinese) or in similar fields can be considered for admission. If admitted, these students are often required to make up deficiencies in their course work. This can result in a lengthening of the normative time to degree (six years).</p>
<p>The department only admits students into the Ph.D program. You must indicate that a Ph.D. is your degree goal on the application materials. Students who have not completed an M.A. degree before beginning study at Berkeley will have to complete the requirements for the M.A. before proceeding to the Ph.D. program. After completion of the M.A. requirements (course- work and thesis), students are evaluated for permission to proceed to the Ph.D. portion of the program. Students who have completed an M.A. degree before beginning study at Berkeley may apply for admission directly to the Ph.D. program. After one year in the Ph.D. program, such students will be evaluated before being permitted to continue in the program.</p>
<p>U.C. Berkeley graduate students from other disciplines who are considering transferring into the degree program in Japanese or Chinese language undergo the same faculty review as first- time applicants, however, they do not complete the Graduate Application. Students in this category should contact Graduate Degrees, 302 Sproul Hall, University of California, Berkeley, CA 94720-5900 for a Petition for Change of Major or Degree Goal and the department <a href="mailto://jmj@berkeley.edu" target="_blank">Graduate Assistant</a>
 for a checklist of materials that will need to be submitted.</p>

<p>The length of time needed to complete an advanced degree in the department depends on financial considerations, the extent of the student's earlier preparation, and other factors. Under optimum conditions, the M.A. can be earned in two years and the Ph.D. in an additional three to four years.</p>
<p><strong>Step by Step.</strong> To learn how best to prepare for study at the graduate level in the humanities and the social sciences, current undergraduates may find useful<a href="http://stepbystep.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank"> Step by Step</a>
, a resource for UC Berkeley students to enrich their undergraduate academic experience and to prepare for graduate school.</p>

</div>

</div>

</div>

</div>

]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Uniform minimum requirements for admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A minimum grade-point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant comes from a country or political entity (e.g. Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, 230 on the computer-based test, 90 on the iBT test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Enough undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants who already hold a graduate degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees as evidence of broad research training, not as vocational training certificates; therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to take up new subject matter on a serious level without undertaking a graduate program, unless the fields are completely dissimilar.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may only apply to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <p>Any applicant who was previously registered at Berkeley as a graduate student, no matter how briefly, must apply for readmission, not admission, even if the new application is to a different program.</p> <h4>Required documents for admissions applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts:  </strong><span style="font-size:1em">Upload unofficial transcripts with the application for the departmental initial review. Official transcripts of all college-level work will be required </span><strong style="font-size:1em">if admitted</strong><span style="font-size:1em">. Official transcripts must be in sealed envelopes as issued by the school(s) you have attended. Request a current transcript from every post-secondary school that you have attended, including community colleges, summer sessions, and extension programs.</span> 	<div class="gmail_default">If you have attended Berkeley, upload unofficial transcript with the application for the departmental initial review. Official transcript with evidence of degree conferral <em><strong>will not</strong></em> be required if admitted.</div> 	</li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants can request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, not the Graduate Division.</li> 	<li><strong>Evidence of English language proficiency:</strong> All applicants from countries in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This requirement applies to applicants from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, and most European countries. However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a U.S. university may submit an official transcript from the U.S. university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement: 1) courses in English as a Second Language, 2) courses conducted in a language other than English, 3) courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and 4) courses of a non-academic nature. If applicants have previously been denied admission to Berkeley on the basis of their English language proficiency, they must submit new test scores that meet the current minimum from one of the standardized tests.</li> </ol>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Normative Time Requirements</h3>
<p class="Normal1">Effective 2004, the student has ten semesters of Normative Time after entering the program to complete the Qualifying Examinations and submit a petition to advance to candidacy to be eligible for the Dean's Normative Time Fellowship (DNTF). If the student successfully advances before or during the tenth semester, he or she is awarded a Normative Time grant for one year of support, which must be used within the two-year Normative Time in candidacy period (F.3.7). If a student advances in the eleventh or twelfth semester, he or she is eligible for one semeter of the DNTF, and must claim it within the student's remaining time in candidacy.</p>
<h3>Time to Advancement</h3>
<h4 class="Normal1CxSpFirst">Curriculum</h4>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%"><colgroup><col class="codecol" /><col class="titlecol" /><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol" /></colgroup><tbody><tr class="even areaheader firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader">Courses Required</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">EA&#160;LANG&#160;200</td><td>Proseminar: Approaches to East Asian Studies</td><td class="hourscol">2,4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Graduate Seminars:</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left: 20px;"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Three (4 units each) in Japanese language and area electives (8 units) before proceeding to the Ph.D.</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left: 20px;"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Two graduate seminars and one course (Graduate/Upper Division) outside EALC in cognate discipline after proceeding to the Ph.D.</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<coursestext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Japanese Language</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JAPAN C225" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="838">
<span class="code">JAPAN&#160;C225</span> 
<span class="title">Readings in Japanese Buddhist Texts</span> 
<span class="hours">2 or 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">This seminar serves as an introduction to a broad range of Japanese Buddhist literature belonging to different historical periods and genres, including liturgical texts; monastic records, rules, and ritual manuals; doctrinal treatises; biographies of monks; and histories of Buddhism in Japan. Students are required to do all the readings in the original languages, which are classical Chinese (Kanbun) and classical Japanese. It will also serve as a tools and methods course, covering basic reference</span><span class="deschide"> works and secondary scholarship in the field of Japanese Buddhism. The content of the course will be adjusted from semester to semester to accommodate the needs and interests of the students.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="838" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Japanese/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Also listed as:</strong> BUDDSTD&#160;C225</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JAPAN 230" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="170">
<span class="code">JAPAN&#160;230</span> 
<span class="title">Seminar in Classical Japanese Poetry</span> 
<span class="hours">2 or 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Topics run from Japan's earliest extant poetic anthologies in Chinese (Kaifuso) or Japanese (Man'yoshu) to medieval linked verse (renga) and Edo haikai.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="170" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Two semesters of classical Japanese</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit as topic varies. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Japanese/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JAPAN C231" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="515">
<span class="code">JAPAN&#160;C231</span> 
<span class="title">Japanese Studies: Past, Present... and Future?</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offers an overview of the history and current state of the field in Japanese studies, with faculty presentations, selected readings, and orientation sessions with East Asian Library staff to acquaint participants with relevant resources for research. Requirements will include completion of course readings and preparation of a research prospectus.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="515" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1 hour of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Japanese/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Also listed as:</strong> HISTORY&#160;C231</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JAPAN 232" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="118">
<span class="code">JAPAN&#160;232</span> 
<span class="title">Japanese Bibliography</span> 
<span class="hours">2 or 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">An introduction to research tools for Japanese studies. The course gives primary consideration to literary sources but also presents an overview of basic texts and web sites dealing with bibliographical citation, lexicography, history, religion, fine arts, geography, personal names, biographies, genealogies, and calendrical calculation. Internet access is required.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="118" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Reading ability in modern Japanese; classical Japanese helpful but not required</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Japanese/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JAPAN 234" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="588">
<span class="code">JAPAN&#160;234</span> 
<span class="title">Seminar in Classical Japanese Drama</span> 
<span class="hours">2 or 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Topics may include examples from the Noh, Kyogen, Joruri, or Kabuki theaters.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="588" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Two semesters of classical Japanese</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit as topic varies. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Japanese/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JAPAN 240" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="79">
<span class="code">JAPAN&#160;240</span> 
<span class="title">Seminar in Classical Japanese Texts</span> 
<span class="hours">2 or 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Topics may include works of Heian fiction such as The Tale of Genji (Genji monogatari) and memoirs such as The Pillow Book (Makura no soshi).
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="79" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Two semesters of classical Japanese</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit as topic varies. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Japanese/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> The grading option will be decided by the instructor when the class is offered. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JAPAN 255" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="116">
<span class="code">JAPAN&#160;255</span> 
<span class="title">Seminar in Prewar Japanese Literature</span> 
<span class="hours">2 or 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Reading and critical evaluation of selected texts in prewar (roughly the 1860s though the 1940s) Japanese literature and literary and cultural criticism. Texts change with each offering of the course.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="116" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing and consent of instructor</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit as topic varies. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Japanese/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JAPAN 259" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="152">
<span class="code">JAPAN&#160;259</span> 
<span class="title">Seminar in Postwar Japanese Literature</span> 
<span class="hours">2 or 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Reading and critical evaluation of selected texts in postwar (roughly the 1940s through the present) Japanese literature and literary and cultural criticism. Texts change with each offering of the course.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="152" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing and permission of instructor</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit as topic varies. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Japanese/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JAPAN 298" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="766">
<span class="code">JAPAN&#160;298</span> 
<span class="title">Directed Study for Graduate Students</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Special tutorial or seminar on selected topics not covered by available courses or seminars.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="766" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-8 hours of independent study per week</p><p class=""><strong>Summer:</strong> <br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>3 weeks - 5-40 hours of independent study per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>6 weeks - 2.5-20 hours of independent study per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>8 weeks - 1.5-15 hours of independent study per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>10 weeks - 1.5-12 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Japanese/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JAPAN 299" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="650">
<span class="code">JAPAN&#160;299</span> 
<span class="title">Thesis Preparation and Related Research</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">


<div id="650" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of thesis supervisor and graduate adviser</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p><p class=""><strong>Summer:</strong> <br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>6 weeks - 2.5-20 hours of independent study per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>8 weeks - 1.5-15 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Japanese/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JAPAN 601" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="979">
<span class="code">JAPAN&#160;601</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study for Master's Students</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Individual study for the comprehensive or language requirements in consultation with the graduate adviser. Units may not be used to meet either unit or residence requirements for a master's degree.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="979" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of graduate adviser</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p><p class=""><strong>Summer:</strong> <br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>6 weeks - 2.5-20 hours of independent study per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>8 weeks - 1.5-15 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Japanese/Graduate examination preparation</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=JAPAN 602" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="503">
<span class="code">JAPAN&#160;602</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study for Doctoral Students</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Individual study in consultation with the major field adviser, intended to provide an opportunity for qualified students to prepare for various examinations required of candidates for the Ph.D.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="503" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-8 hours of independent study per week</p><p class=""><strong>Summer:</strong> <br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>6 weeks - 2.5-20 hours of independent study per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>8 weeks - 1.5-15 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Japanese/Graduate examination preparation</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

