<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The Designated Emphasis (DE) in Critical Theory permits interested students to specialize in critical theory and to obtain certification of this specialization, while pursuing a PhD in an established UC Berkeley department. Critical Theory is not an independent degree granting program. Students admitted to the DE and completing the requirements will receive a parenthetical notation to that effect on their doctoral degrees.</p>
<p>Critical Theory is typically associated with the work of the Frankfurt School, and that tradition of theory figures significantly in the DE curriculum. However, the program at Berkeley broadens and extends the meaning of critical theory to include 19th century philosophers of critique and contemporary critical theoretical work on culture, religion, nationalism, post-nationalism, identity, and capitalism. Above all, Critical Theory at UC Berkeley emphasizes the centrality of theoretical critique to the examination of contemporary values, conflicts among schemes of values, the powers that organize political, social, cultural, and economic life, and modes of justification and legitimization for cultural inquiry and political analysis.</p>
<h3>Undergraduate Program</h3>
<p>There is no undergraduate program in Critical Theory.</p>
<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="/archive/2014-15/graduate/degree-programs/critical-theory/">Critical Theory</a>
: Designated Emphasis (DE)</p>

  
]]>
</text>
<coursestext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Critical Theory</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=CRIT TH 200" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="83">
<span class="code">CRIT&#160;TH&#160;200</span> 
<span class="title">Critique in 19th-Century Thought</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">This course will examine various formulations of critique in 19th-century theory. Thinkers who may be studied include Kant, Hegel, Marx, Nietzsche, and Weber, though the selection will vary by instructor. This is the &quot;foundations&quot; course for the Designated Emphasis in Critical Theory.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="83" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Admission to the critical theory designated emphasis or consent of instructor</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Critical Theory Graduate Group/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Instructor:</strong> Brown</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=CRIT TH 205" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="289">
<span class="code">CRIT&#160;TH&#160;205</span> 
<span class="title">The Classical Frankfurt School: The First Generation of Critical Theory</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">This course will explore the founding texts of the Frankfurt School's first generation: Horkheimer, Adorno, Benjamin, Marcuse, Lowenthal, and their circle. It will follow the development of critical theory through its Weimer years, American exile, and return to postwar Germany.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="289" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Admission to the critical theory designated emphasis or consent of instructor</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Critical Theory Graduate Group/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Instructor:</strong> Jay</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=CRIT TH 240" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="784">
<span class="code">CRIT&#160;TH&#160;240</span> 
<span class="title">Contemporary Critique and Critical Theory</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">This course will explore various contemporary engagements with the foundations of critical theory in relation to other histories and locations. Topics will vary by instructor but may include: post-continental political theory, critique and the problem of political dissent and citizenship, gender and race in relation to critical practices, psychoanalysis, and literary and art theory and criticism.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="784" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Admission to the critical theory designated emphasis or consent of instructor</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with consent of instructor. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Critical Theory Graduate Group/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=CRIT TH 290" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="248">
<span class="code">CRIT&#160;TH&#160;290</span> 
<span class="title">Critical Theory Elective</span> 
<span class="hours">2 - 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow overflow">Critical Theory electives are taught by core and affiliated faculty in the Critical Theory program and offer important treatments of theoretical materials significant to the intellectual traditions of the program's course of study in nineteenth-century social theory and philosophy, Frankfurt School and related currents in theory and criticism, and contemporary critical theory. In a typical Critical Theory elective, theoretical materials are presented in dialogue with an anthropological, artistic/aesthetic</span><span class="deschide">, economic, educational, historical, philosophical, political, rhetorical, sociological, or other disciplinary matrix that constitutes the course's primary materials for study and inquiry.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="248" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Admission to the Critical Theory Designated Emphasis or consent of the instructor</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong>  Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2-3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Critical Theory Graduate Group/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

