<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<p class="Normal1">The Department of Linguistics takes a broad approach to the study of language. The department covers not only the standard &quot;core&quot; areas of phonetics, phonology, morphology, syntax and semantics, but also historical linguistics, field linguistics and language documentation, cognitive linguistics, psycholinguistics, and language in society. The Graduate Program trains students to do the kind of research that seeks to discover and provide explanations for general properties of linguistic form, meaning, and usage. The department has a strong commitment to language documentation as well as to cutting edge theoretical training.</p>
<p class="Normal1">Berkeley's graduate program is a PhD program in which students earn an MA along the way.</p>


]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Uniform minimum requirements for admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A minimum grade-point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant comes from a country or political entity (e.g. Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, 230 on the computer-based test, 90 on the iBT test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Enough undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants who already hold a graduate degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees as evidence of broad research training, not as vocational training certificates; therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to take up new subject matter on a serious level without undertaking a graduate program, unless the fields are completely dissimilar.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may only apply to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <p>Any applicant who was previously registered at Berkeley as a graduate student, no matter how briefly, must apply for readmission, not admission, even if the new application is to a different program.</p> <h4>Required documents for admissions applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts:  </strong><span style="font-size:1em">Upload unofficial transcripts with the application for the departmental initial review. Official transcripts of all college-level work will be required </span><strong style="font-size:1em">if admitted</strong><span style="font-size:1em">. Official transcripts must be in sealed envelopes as issued by the school(s) you have attended. Request a current transcript from every post-secondary school that you have attended, including community colleges, summer sessions, and extension programs.</span> 	<div class="gmail_default">If you have attended Berkeley, upload unofficial transcript with the application for the departmental initial review. Official transcript with evidence of degree conferral <em><strong>will not</strong></em> be required if admitted.</div> 	</li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants can request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, not the Graduate Division.</li> 	<li><strong>Evidence of English language proficiency:</strong> All applicants from countries in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This requirement applies to applicants from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, and most European countries. However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a U.S. university may submit an official transcript from the U.S. university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement: 1) courses in English as a Second Language, 2) courses conducted in a language other than English, 3) courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and 4) courses of a non-academic nature. If applicants have previously been denied admission to Berkeley on the basis of their English language proficiency, they must submit new test scores that meet the current minimum from one of the standardized tests.</li> </ol>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
<h4>Curriculum</h4>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%"><colgroup><col class="codecol" /><col class="titlecol" /><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol" /></colgroup><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol">LINGUIS&#160;200</td><td>Graduate Proseminar in Linguistics</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">LINGUIS&#160;202</td><td>Course Not Available</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">LINGUIS&#160;110</td><td>Introduction to Phonetics and Phonology</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">LINGUIS&#160;211A</td><td>Advanced Phonological Theory</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">LINGUIS&#160;220A</td><td>Syntax and Semantics 1</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">LINGUIS&#160;230</td><td>Historical Linguistics</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Structures: Select one of the following:</span></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;211B</div></td><td>Topics in Phonological Theory</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;215</div></td><td>Advanced Morphology</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;220B</div></td><td>Syntax and Semantics II</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Ecologies: Select one of the following:</span></td><td class="hourscol">3-4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;C105</div></td><td>The Mind and Language</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;123</div></td><td>Pragmatics</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;255</div></td><td>Introduction to Sociocultural Linguistics</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;181</div></td><td>Lexical Semantics</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;205</div></td><td>Advanced Cognitive Linguistics</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;210</div></td><td>Phonetic Theory</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;250A</div></td><td>Course Not Available</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;250B</div></td><td>Sociolinguistic Analysis: Language Contact</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;250C</div></td><td>Sociolinguistic Analysis: Language and Gender</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;250D</div></td><td>Sociolinguistic Analysis: Conversation/Discourse Analysis</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;250E</div></td><td>Sociolinguistic Analysis: Endangered Languages</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Select additional electives from Structures list, Ecologies list, or the following:</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;231</div></td><td>Course Not Available</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;234</div></td><td>Indo-European Linguistics</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;245</div></td><td>Anthropological Linguistics</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;270</div></td><td>Structure of a Particular Language</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;275</div></td><td>Course Not Available</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;290A</div></td><td>Topics in Linguistic Theory: Syntax</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;290B</div></td><td>Topics in Linguistic Theory: Semantics</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;290D</div></td><td>Topics in Linguistic Theory: Pragmatics</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;290E</div></td><td>Topics in Linguistic Theory: Phonology</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;290F</div></td><td>Topics in Linguistic Theory: Diachronic Linguistics</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;290H</div></td><td>Topics in Linguistic Theory: Linguistic Reconstruction</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;290L</div></td><td>Additional Seminar on Special Topics to Be Announced</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;290M</div></td><td>Topics in Linguistic Theory: Psycholinguistics</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left: 20px;">LINGUIS&#160;290R</div></td><td>Topics in Linguistic Theory: Language and Thought</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol">LINGUIS&#160;240A<br /> &#160;&#160;&amp;&#160;LINGUIS&#160;240B</td><td>Field Methods<br />&#160;&#160; and Field Methods</td><td class="hourscol">8</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<facultytext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Professors</h3>
<p class="facitem"><strong>Andrew Garrett, <em>Professor</em>.</strong> Linguistics, English, California, language change, Indo-European languages, historical linguistics, northern California Indian languages, linguistic structure, typology, ancient Greek, Latin, Irish, Oceanic languages.<br/>
<a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14704" target="_blank">Research Profile</a>
</p>

<p class="facitem"><strong>Gary B. Holland, <em>Professor</em>.</strong> Poetics, historical linguistics, Indo-European linguistics, early Indo-European languages, linguistic typology, historical syntax, history of linguistics.<br/>
<a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14854" target="_blank">Research Profile</a>
</p>

<p class="facitem"><strong>Larry M. Hyman, <em>Professor</em>.</strong> Linguistics, phonological theory, African languages, the Niger-Congo, Bantu, language structure, comparative and historical study of the Bantu language family.<br/>
<a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14976" target="_blank">Research Profile</a>
</p>

<p class="facitem"><strong>Sharon Inkelas, <em>Professor</em>.</strong> Morphology, phonology, reduplication, child phonology.<br/>
<a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14978" target="_blank">Research Profile</a>
</p>

<p class="facitem"><strong>Keith Johnson, <em>Professor</em>.</strong> Phonetics.<br/>
<a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14117" target="_blank">Research Profile</a>
</p>

<p class="facitem"><strong>George P. Lakoff, <em>Professor</em>.</strong> Mathematics, literature, philosophy, cognitive linguistics, the neural theory of language, conceptual systems, conceptual metaphor, syntax-semantics-pragmatics, the application of cognitive linguistics to politics.<br/>
<a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14994" target="_blank">Research Profile</a>
</p>

<p class="facitem"><strong>Terry Regier, <em>Professor</em>.</strong> Computational methods, language and thought, semantic universals.<br/>
<a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15264" target="_blank">Research Profile</a>
</p>

<p class="facitem"><strong>Eve E. Sweetser, <em>Professor</em>.</strong> Subjectivity, syntax, semantics, cognitive linguistics, historical linguistics, Celtic languages, speech act theory, semantic change, grammaticalization, gesture, metaphor, iconicity, viewpoint, construction grammar, semantics of grammatical constructions.<br/>
<a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15515" target="_blank">Research Profile</a>
</p>

<h4>Associate Professors</h4>
<p class="facitem"><strong>Susanne Gahl, <em>Associate Professor</em>.</strong></p>
<p class="facitem"><strong>Lev D. Michael, <em>Associate Professor</em>.</strong></p>
<p class="facitem"><strong>Line Mikkelsen, <em>Associate Professor</em>.</strong> Morphology, syntax, semantics, Germanic and California languages.<br/>
<a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15344" target="_blank">Research Profile</a>
</p>

<p class="facitem"><strong>Richard Rhodes, <em>Associate Professor</em>.</strong> American Indian languages, lexical semantics, lexicography, Algonquian languages, Ojibwe, Mixe-Zoquean languages, mixed languages, Michif (Métchif), Sayula Popoluca (Sayuleño).<br/>
<a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15398" target="_blank">Research Profile</a>
</p>

<h4>Assistant Professors</h4>
<p class="facitem"><strong>Peter S. Jenks, <em>Assistant Professor</em>.</strong></p>
<p class="facitem"><strong>Susan Lin, <em>Assistant Professor</em>.</strong></p>
]]>
</facultytext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

