<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<p>UC Berkeley offers an interdisciplinary program of graduate study in Ancient History and Ancient Near Eastern and Mediterranean Archaeology (AHMA). The program is conducted by an interdisciplinary group that includes more than twenty faculty members affiliated with seven different Berkeley departments and the Graduate Theological Union. A chair, a graduate adviser, and student affairs officers administer the program.</p>
<p>The AHMA program offers PhD degrees in areas that combine work in archaeology and history and related disciplines of ancient studies. Most of its graduates have successfully secured teaching positions in Departments of Classics, Art History, History, Anthropology or Near Eastern Studies in colleges and universities in the US or abroad, including Bar-Ilan, Haifa, Volos, Oxford, Toronto, Columbia, Madison, Austin, and Penn.</p>
<p>Students are not admitted to work specifically for the MA degree, although those working toward the PhD may file for an MA after fulfillment of the requirements for Stage I. Students work closely with faculty in courses, seminars, and independent research projects to develop independent thought as well as a thorough knowledge of their fields and their critical methods.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Uniform minimum requirements for admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A minimum grade-point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant comes from a country or political entity (e.g. Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, 230 on the computer-based test, 90 on the iBT test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Enough undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants who already hold a graduate degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees as evidence of broad research training, not as vocational training certificates; therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to take up new subject matter on a serious level without undertaking a graduate program, unless the fields are completely dissimilar.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may only apply to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <p>Any applicant who was previously registered at Berkeley as a graduate student, no matter how briefly, must apply for readmission, not admission, even if the new application is to a different program.</p> <h4>Required documents for admissions applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts:  </strong><span style="font-size:1em">Upload unofficial transcripts with the application for the departmental initial review. Official transcripts of all college-level work will be required </span><strong style="font-size:1em">if admitted</strong><span style="font-size:1em">. Official transcripts must be in sealed envelopes as issued by the school(s) you have attended. Request a current transcript from every post-secondary school that you have attended, including community colleges, summer sessions, and extension programs.</span> 	<div class="gmail_default">If you have attended Berkeley, upload unofficial transcript with the application for the departmental initial review. Official transcript with evidence of degree conferral <em><strong>will not</strong></em> be required if admitted.</div> 	</li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants can request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, not the Graduate Division.</li> 	<li><strong>Evidence of English language proficiency:</strong> All applicants from countries in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This requirement applies to applicants from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, and most European countries. However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a U.S. university may submit an official transcript from the U.S. university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement: 1) courses in English as a Second Language, 2) courses conducted in a language other than English, 3) courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and 4) courses of a non-academic nature. If applicants have previously been denied admission to Berkeley on the basis of their English language proficiency, they must submit new test scores that meet the current minimum from one of the standardized tests.</li> </ol>
<p> 
</p><h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the Program</h3>
<p></p>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">The AHMA program is open to students with a BA degree in a relevant field of study (such as Classics, Near Eastern Studies, History, or History of Art) that have completed at least one year of undergraduate work in ancient history, ancient art, archaeology, or related fields. Applicants primarily interested in the Greek and Roman worlds should be prepared to undertake advanced work in either Greek or Latin and its culture, and also should have basic competence in the second of these two languages. Applicants primarily interested in the ancient Near East and Egypt do not have to display competence in one of the area’s ancient languages before applying, but to do so may strengthen their application considerably.</p>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Students who have already acquired the MA degree in a relevant field are especially encouraged to apply, and will be considered for direct admission to the PhD program. The AHMA faculty as a group approves all applicants for admission. AHMA policy is to limit enrollment to the number of students who can be adequately supported for the first five years of their graduate career. Although AHMA receives around 50 applications per year, its admission quota (set by Graduate Division) is currently only around 5-6, with the expectation that 2-3 new students will enroll each fall. Competition therefore is extremely keen. As a result, while some applicants may be rejected for lack of preparation or for undistinguished academic records, a substantial number who are capable of doing good graduate work unfortunately also must be denied admission.</p>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">The AHMA faculty judges and ranks applicants on a combination of criteria that includes:</p>
<ul>
	<li class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Preparation to undertake advanced scholarly work</li>
	<li class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Academic distinction as reflected in overall GPA, major GPA, and junior and senior year GPA, as well as awards, prizes, or publications</li>
	<li class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">A minimum of three letters of recommendation</li>
	<li class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">GRE scores (use 2901: Classics, or 2609: Classical Languages for scores to be reported by ETS)</li>
	<li class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">A statement of purpose, which should be clearly and cogently written and indicate why the applicant is interested in the AHMA program and where his or her specialization might lie</li>
	<li class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">A scholarly writing sample of no more than 25 pages and indicating the origin of the writing sample (i.e. a class paper, senior honors thesis, MA thesis </li>
</ul>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">An applicant with an MA is expected to offer substantially stronger preparation than one with only a BA. Applications must be submitted electronically either via Graduate Division’s online application or via the link on the AHMA website. The online application process for fall normally opens in early September.</p>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">The deadline for all online applications is December 15th. We request that applicants email all their supplemental material, such as all official transcripts, writing samples, applicant Reading List in Ancient Languages, or any other material, as PDFs to <a href="mailto:casmaadm@berkeley.edu">casmaadm@berkeley.edu</a>
. They will be manually uploaded by the admissions staff into the applicant’s online application.</p>

]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
<h4 class="Normal1">Curriculum</h4>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%"><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Six graduate or upper-division courses (first year), including the following:</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left: 20px;"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">Methodology course</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><div style="margin-left: 20px;"><span class="courselistcomment commentindent">AHMA seminar</span></div></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Electives per approved study list</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Four graduate or upper-division courses, appropriate to the student's major, minor, and outside fields</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<coursestext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Ancient History and Mediterranean Archaeology</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=AHMA 210" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="470">
<span class="code">AHMA&#160;210</span> 
<span class="title">Ancient History and Mediterranean Archaeology Interdisciplinary Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">2 or 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Team-taught by faculty from two different departments. The purpose is not only to expose students to a discipline other than their own, but to engage them directly in the application of that discipline to their own research interests. The topic and instructors will vary from year to year.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="470" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Ancient History and Med. Arch./Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=AHMA 299" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="259">
<span class="code">AHMA&#160;299</span> 
<span class="title">Special Study</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Topics and instructors will vary from year to year. Special individual study for qualified graduate students. Individual study and research, including archaeological fieldwork or laboratory projects, in consultation with instructor on subject matter not covered in scheduled course offerings.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="259" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing or consent of instructor</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 4-16 hours of independent study per week</p><p class=""><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 7.5-30 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Four hours of independent study per week per unit, including consultation. Seven and one-half to thirty hours of independent study per week, including consultation.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Ancient History and Med. Arch./Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

