<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<p>The PhD in Performance Studies provides an interdisciplinary and individually-crafted curriculum directed at advanced studies in the literatures, performances, cultural contexts, and theories of performance throughout the world. The PhD program is administered by an interdisciplinary graduate group composed of faculty from a wide range of related departments. Students in the PhD program in performance studies conduct research in a diverse array of interdisciplinary methodologies, on projects spanning the fields of theater, dance, and performance studies.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Uniform minimum requirements for admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A minimum grade-point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant comes from a country or political entity (e.g. Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, 230 on the computer-based test, 90 on the iBT test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Enough undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants who already hold a graduate degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees as evidence of broad research training, not as vocational training certificates; therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to take up new subject matter on a serious level without undertaking a graduate program, unless the fields are completely dissimilar.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may only apply to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <p>Any applicant who was previously registered at Berkeley as a graduate student, no matter how briefly, must apply for readmission, not admission, even if the new application is to a different program.</p> <h4>Required documents for admissions applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts:  </strong><span style="font-size:1em">Upload unofficial transcripts with the application for the departmental initial review. Official transcripts of all college-level work will be required </span><strong style="font-size:1em">if admitted</strong><span style="font-size:1em">. Official transcripts must be in sealed envelopes as issued by the school(s) you have attended. Request a current transcript from every post-secondary school that you have attended, including community colleges, summer sessions, and extension programs.</span> 	<div class="gmail_default">If you have attended Berkeley, upload unofficial transcript with the application for the departmental initial review. Official transcript with evidence of degree conferral <em><strong>will not</strong></em> be required if admitted.</div> 	</li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants can request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, not the Graduate Division.</li> 	<li><strong>Evidence of English language proficiency:</strong> All applicants from countries in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This requirement applies to applicants from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, and most European countries. However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a U.S. university may submit an official transcript from the U.S. university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement: 1) courses in English as a Second Language, 2) courses conducted in a language other than English, 3) courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and 4) courses of a non-academic nature. If applicants have previously been denied admission to Berkeley on the basis of their English language proficiency, they must submit new test scores that meet the current minimum from one of the standardized tests.</li> </ol>
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the Program</h3>
<p class="Normal1">The Graduate Group admissions committee seeks applicants with qualities that will enable them to succeed in an intensive interdisciplinary program: creativity and analytical skills, practical experience, individual initiative, and intellectual rigor. Priority will be given to applicants whose research interests dovetail well with current faculty resources. Candidates holding a Bachelor’s or Master’s degree in theater, literature, performance studies, dance, or any appropriate humanities-related field are eligible to apply for admissions. The Graduate Group is particularly interested in applicants who have already formulated a specific focus of interest, including professional theater or dance practitioners who demonstrate a capacity for and training in advanced scholarly study.</p>
<p>As part of the application, you will be asked to submit the following:</p>
<ol>
	<li class="Normal1">All college transcripts</li>
	<li class="Normal1">Three letters of recommendation</li>
	<li class="Normal1"> GRE scores (less than 5 years old) &amp; TOEFL scores (if applicable)</li>
	<li class="Normal1">Resume/CV </li>
	<li class="Normal1">Personal Statement </li>
	<li class="Normal1">Statement of Purpose </li>
	<li class="Normal1">Critical Writing Sample (15-20 pages)</li>
</ol>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Normative Time Requirements</h3>
<h5 class="Normal1CxSpFirst">Normative Time to Advancement</h5>
<p class="Normal1CxSpFirst">Normative Time to Advancement is 3 years.</p>
<h5 class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Normative Time in Candidacy</h5>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Normative Time in Candidacy is 3 years.</p>
<h5 class="Normal1CxSpLast">Total Normative Time</h5>
<p class="Normal1CxSpLast">Total Normative Time is 6 years.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Time to Advancement</h3>
<h5>Curriculum</h5>
<p>The following is a breakdown of requirements to be fulfilled during the student’s first five semesters of study. All courses must be taken for letter grades.</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%"><colgroup><col class="codecol" /><col class="titlecol" /><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol" /></colgroup><tbody><tr class="even areaheader firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader">Core Colloquia </span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">THEATER&#160;200A</td><td>Introductory Colloquium on Interdisciplinary Research in Performance</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">THEATER&#160;200B</td><td>Research Colloquium</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">THEATER&#160;200B</td><td>Research Colloquium</td><td class="hourscol">2</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader">Core Seminars</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">THEATER&#160;201</td><td>Performance Theory</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">THEATER&#160;202</td><td>Methodologies in Performance Studies</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">THEATER&#160;203</td><td>Performance Practicum: Lab Run</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader">Electives</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Select nine elective courses, 2-6 units per course</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader">Pedagogy Courses</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">See below for details</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader">Theater Practice </span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Participation in at least one production activity beyond THEATER&#160;203</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h6>Pedagogy Courses</h6>
<p>To prepare for appointment as a Graduate Student Instructor (GSI), students are required to take a 300-level pedagogy course for Reading and Composition. Students normally fulfill this requirement by taking <span class="sc_courseinline">COLWRIT&#160;375</span> in the fall semester of the 1st year (this course is not usually offered in the spring). While taking <span class="sc_courseinline">COLWRIT&#160;375</span> during the first semester as a GSI is allowed, we have found it to be much more valuable to complete the course in advance of teaching for the first time. For those 1st-year students who have stipend support for their second year (and therefore won’t teach until the third year), the pedagogy course may be taken during the fall semester of the 2nd year. Also, GSIs for TDPS enroll each semester in <span class="sc_courseinline">THEATER&#160;300</span> with their teaching supervisor.</p>

<h5>Foreign Language</h5>
<p>Pass a language exam, usually in the Fall semester of the first year, or take the needed language class.</p>
<h5>QE</h5>
<p>Students sit their Qualifying Exams in their sixth semester before proceeding to the dissertation.</p>
<hr/>
<h3>Time in Candidacy</h3>
<h5>Prospectus</h5>
<p>During the dissertation phase, students are expected to submit a copy of their dissertation prospectus (by the end of the seventh semester).</p>
<h5>Dissertation</h5>
<p>Students are expected to complete their dissertations within the normative time frame (i.e., 12 semesters from the start of the program), and give a public presentation of their research (in the ninth semester).</p>
]]>
</doctoraldegreerequirementstext>
<coursestext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Performance Studies</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=THEATER 200A" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="590">
<span class="code">THEATER&#160;200A</span> 
<span class="title">Introductory Colloquium on Interdisciplinary Research in Performance</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">This course is designed to introduce graduate students to the research resources of the University, to the methodologies and research interests of the faculty affiliated with the Ph.D. program, to the demands of a professional academic career, and to trends and developments in theater, dance, and performance studies.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="590" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">


<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of colloquium per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Theater, Dance, and Performance St/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=THEATER 200B" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="253">
<span class="code">THEATER&#160;200B</span> 
<span class="title">Research Colloquium</span> 
<span class="hours">2 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">This course is designed to provide an opportunity for graduate students to work with one another to advance their individual research projects and present their ongoing work.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="253" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 2 hours of colloquium per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Theater, Dance, and Performance St/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=THEATER 201" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="933">
<span class="code">THEATER&#160;201</span> 
<span class="title">Performance Theory</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">This core seminar for graduate students focuses on key issues in the theory of performance, with an emphasis on contemporary theoretical inquiry. Topics can include issues of representation and identity, presence, community, social efficacy, space, corporeality, audience, and transnational flows.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="933" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit as topic varies. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Theater, Dance, and Performance St/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Dramatic Art 201</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=THEATER 202" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="356">
<span class="code">THEATER&#160;202</span> 
<span class="title">Methodologies in Performance Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">The study of different approaches and contemporary methodologies for analyzing performances of various kinds within their cultural and historical context. Specific methodologies can include archival research, field methods, etc. The specific focus in any one course is contingent upon the focus of the instructor.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="356" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit as topic varies. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Theater, Dance, and Performance St/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Dramatic Art 202</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=THEATER 203" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="613">
<span class="code">THEATER&#160;203</span> 
<span class="title">Performance Practicum: Lab Run</span> 
<span class="hours">2 - 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">This course is constructed around the making of performance, culminating in Lab Run, an event created, directed, and/or performed by graduate students. Lab Run will receive public performances near the end of the semester. The course is also conceived as a forum for exploring the relationship between live performance and the critical discourses of performance studies.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="613" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1.5-3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Theater, Dance, and Performance St/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> The grading option will be decided by the instructor when the class is offered. </p><p class=""><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Dramatic Art 203</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=THEATER 266" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="339">
<span class="code">THEATER&#160;266</span> 
<span class="title">Special Topics: Theater Arts</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Topics vary from semester to semester and have included The Power of Music and Poetry in the Theater; Modern Drama and Theater, 1940 to the Present; Theaters, Tricksters, and Cultural Exchange; Art as Social Action; and The Invisible World (Process Seminar).
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="339" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of lecture and 3-12 hours of laboratory per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Theater, Dance, and Performance St/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Dramatic Art 266</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=THEATER 277" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="817">
<span class="code">THEATER&#160;277</span> 
<span class="title">Special Studies in Directing</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Advanced practice in play direction.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="817" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Advancement to candidacy for the Ph.D. and consent of instructor</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of studio per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Theater, Dance, and Performance St/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Dramatic Art 277</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=THEATER 294" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="471">
<span class="code">THEATER&#160;294</span> 
<span class="title">Directed Research</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Meetings to be arranged, either individually or as a group to explore fields not covered in courses listed elsewhere in Dramatic Art's offerings. May be taken by students engaged in writing dissertations.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="471" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing in Dramatic Art and consent of instructor</p><p class=""><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> A maximum of 12 units may be divided among several instructors during a semester.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0-0 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Theater, Dance, and Performance St/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=THEATER 299" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="103">
<span class="code">THEATER&#160;299</span> 
<span class="title">Special Study</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">May be taken when preparing prospectus, graduate portfolio, and/or oral presentation before qualifying oral examination. May not be substituted for available seminars.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="103" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of independent study per week</p><p class=""><strong>Summer:</strong> <br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>6 weeks - 2.5-10 hours of independent study per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>8 weeks - 1-7.5 hours of independent study per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>10 weeks - 1.5-6 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Theater, Dance, and Performance St/Graduate</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p><p class=""><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Dramatic Art 299</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=THEATER 300" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="203">
<span class="code">THEATER&#160;300</span> 
<span class="title">Professional Preparation: Supervised Teaching in Dramatic Art</span> 
<span class="hours">2 - 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Discussion, problem review and development, course development, supervised practice of teaching.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="203" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Graduate standing, appointment as a teaching assistant or associate, or consent of instructor</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Theater, Dance, and Performance St/Professional course for teachers or prospective teachers</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p><p class=""><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Dramatic Art 300</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=THEATER 340" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="349">
<span class="code">THEATER&#160;340</span> 
<span class="title">Pedagogy for Movement Based Classes - Graduate Level</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">This course studies pedagogical theories and methods. It is designed to prepare graduate students to teach practice-based dance and movement courses. In class teaching exercises will be supported by readings, research projects and assignments on the subject of pedagogy. Development of professional teaching documents such as a teaching philosophy, a sample course syllabus, sample lesson plans, and self-evaluation statements are required.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="349" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong>  Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 6 hours of studio per week</p><p class=""><strong>Summer:</strong> <br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>6 weeks - 15 hours of studio per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>8 weeks - 10 hours of studio per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> There will be one required field trip.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Theater, Dance, and Performance St/Professional course for teachers or prospective teachers</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=THEATER 602" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="343">
<span class="code">THEATER&#160;602</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study for Doctoral Students</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Individual study in consultation with the major field adviser, intended to provide an opportunity for qualified students to prepare themselves for the various examinations required of candidates for the Ph.D.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="343" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Course does not satisfy unit or residence requirements for doctoral degree.</p><p class=""><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p><p class=""><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 15-99 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Hours to be arranged. Hours to be arranged.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p class=""><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Theater, Dance, and Performance St/Graduate examination preparation</p><p class=""><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p><p class=""><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Dramatic Art 602</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

